Web and Native Application Research and Development

https://localhost.international/ leslie@localhost.international +44 (0) 79 8328 5634

#### Introduction

Full-stack developer with 16 years of industry experience, specialising in digital transformation, research and technical project leadership of teams. Actively contributing to open source efforts in creating accessible tools for peer to peer and the decentralised web.

## Recent and Notable Work

Brief descriptions of recent and notable work

## Open Nation - Technical Architect

(via Class 35) November 2020 - present

Technical planning and development of an open platform which gives over 5 million small businesses the ability to engage with and offer their services to large, multinational organisations on creative and technical briefs (such as MasterCard; Open Nation's launch partner).

Highlights: Infrastructure as code with Pulumi, Amazon API Gateway, EBS, ECS and RDS Web Services, TypeScript, Next.js, React, Vercel, Serverless Functions.

### Unicard Smartmobility - Consultant/Lead Developer

(via Humancrafted)

June 2020 - November 2020 (ongoing consultancy)

Ideation, development and planning of the UK's first GBFS and MDS mobility platform that to assist with local councils and city planning for The Department of Transport.

Highlights: AWS Timestream, GBFS, MDS, TypeScript, Pulumi.

### Trayport - App Development Coach

(via Novoda)

August 2020 (future consultancy)

Software development coaching, research and development strategy and technical evaluation for Trayport's technical leadership teams.

Highlights: Development coaching, React Native, TypeScript, Expo, Turtle CLI.

## Expertise

#### Languages

JavaScript and TypeScript Go HTML5, XHTML

**CSS** 

## Analytics and Data

GraphQL MySQL, Postgres and SQLite MongoDB Hypercore and DAT Matomo

## Technologies

Node.js
React
React Native and Expo
Styled Components
Styled JSX
Gatsby and Next.js
Express
ethers and web3
Redux and Recoil
Jest

#### Infrastructure

Amazon Web Services Digital Ocean Pulumi and Terraform

#### Tools

Git GitHub Actions Webpack

Web and Native Application Research and Development

https://localhost.international/ leslie@localhost.international +44 (0) 79 8328 5634

## Work History

Complete work history

#### Technical Director - localhost %

January 2020 - present

Projects include: Mitsubishi MiPulse (at Critical Mass), Open Nation, Unicard Smartmobility and Trayport development coaching (see page 1).

## Fullstack Developer - ustwo

March 2020 - April 2020

Initial development of backend infrastructure for Joe Wicks' Body Coach.

Technologies: AWS, AWS AppSync, Contentful, JavaScript/TypeScript, Terraform.

## Senior Software Engineer - Axate

June 2019 - February 2020

Implementation of Axate's web and AMP wallet.

Projects included: Reach Plc and Wall Street Journal.

Technologies: AMP, AWS, Braintree, Jest, Mixpanel, Preact, React, Redux.

#### Technical Consultant - Genflow

March 2019 - June 2019

Principle developer of Genflow's Matomo analytics platform. Projects included: Anthony Joshua and Grace Beverley.

Technologies: Apollo GraphQL, AWS AppSync, Docker, JavaScript, Gatsby, React, React Native, Matomo, Netlify, Next.is.

### Senior Software Developer - Fidelity International

October 2018 - December 2018

Greenfield development of Fidelity's new End Investor Android application.

Technologies: Apache Cordova, Ionic Native, Java, JavaScript, Jest, React, React Native.

### Senior Developer - Bauer Media

June 2018 - August 2018

Returning as a consultant developer on Project Rosecomb.

Technologies: DADI, React, Redux Sagas, Node.js, TypeScript.

## Expertise (continued)

#### Editors and IDEs

VSCode micro Xcode

Android Studio

#### Services

GitHub GitLab BitBucket JIRA Trello

#### Creative

Figma Sketch

Adobe CC Photoshop Adobe CC Illustrator Adobe CC XD

#### Intermediate Knowledge

Other languages and technologies

Bash, C/C++, C#, Java, JSON, Objective C, TVML, PHP, Pug, Python, Processing.js, Solidity, Swift, VTL and XML

Choo, D3, jQuery, Three.js, Ractive, RequireJS, Svelte and Vue.js

Apache Cordova, Hardhat, Jenkins, OpenX, Subversion and Truffle

Suite

Web and Native Application Research and Development

https://localhost.international/ leslie@localhost.international +44 (0) 79 8328 5634

## Work History (continued)

Developer - Hogarth

April 2018 - May 2018

Development on ad-tech creative management platform Hoxton

Technologies: AWS AppSync, Apollo GraphQL, Lambda, Mocha, Vue.js.

Developer - W12 Studios

February 2018 - March 2018

Development of simple promotional site and CMS for FOX

Technologies: React, Redux Thunk, Craft (Headless)

Senior Developer - DAZN

January 2018 - February 2018

Senior Developer on new Device Porting Team targeting TV platforms and big screen experiences.

Technologies: React, React Native, Ramda, RxJS, MobX, CastLabs, Apache Cordova (Android TV), Crosswalk, TAL.

Senior JavaScript Engineer - Discovery Networks/Eurosport July 2017 - January 2018

Green-field research and development of Eurosport's 2018 Olympics VOD and live streaming video platforms and applications.

Technologies: Apache Cordova, AWS, Akamai, BAM SDK, JavaScript, React, React Native, Redux, RxJS, JWPlayer, Vue.

Technical Director - Currencies Direct

(via Hey Day Studio) November 2016 - May 2017

Digital transformation of all Currencies Direct's websites and apps.

Technologies: Apache Cordova, Java, JavaScript, Node, Objective C, Swift.

## References

George Mayou Partner, Class35

george.mayou@classthirtyfive.com

Dominic Young CEO, Axate dominic@axate.com

Imran Hussain Agile Lead, Discovery/Eurosport Contact details upon request

Rob Green CTO, Monitise Create Contact details upon request

Scott Cooper Head of Innovation, The Sandpit and Sandpit Labs +44 (0) 79 1918 8698

Alex Smith
UX Architect, EF (Special Projects)
Contact details upon request

Web and Native Application Research and Development

https://localhost.international/ leslie@localhost.international +44 (0) 79 8328 5634

## Work History (continued)

#### Lead Developer - Bauer Media

June 2016 - November 2016

Project Rosecomb - Green-field redevelopment of all 59 UK radio properties' digital platforms including Absolute Radio, Magic and KISS.

Technologies: DADI, Dust.js, JavaScript, MongoDB, Node.js, RequireJS.

#### Consultant - Giantsource

April 2016 - June 2016

Research and development for broadcast television Projects included: BBC and Dreamworks.

Technologies: Canvas, JavaScript, Node. js, Ractive, RequireJS, SVG, Handlebars.

#### Senior Developer - Monitise Create (now Etch)

October 2014 - March 2016

Development of Ingenico's 5000 series payment terminal OS and conception of Visa's "Momentum" proximity and location payment service. Clients included: Visa, Santander (KiTTi), Fiat, Ingenico and FIFA.

Technologies: Apache Cordova, AWS,BLE/iBeacon, EMV Wireless, JavaScript, MongoDB, MySQL, NFC, Node.js, Objective C, Ractive, React Native, WebSockets, Swift, Objective C.

#### Senior Developer - Sandpit Labs

December 2013 - September 2014

Research and development of iBeacon proximity and location apps and development of Waves: a social media sentiment analysis insights tool.

Technologies: C++, Chrome Extensions, Django, JavaScript, MongoDB, Node.js, Objective C, Python, Ractive, Redis.

# Senior Frontend Developer (EF Labs) - EF Education First June 2013 - December 2013

Frontend developer of EF SET - the first free online adaptive English test.

Technologies: Composer, Cork PHP Framework, CSS3, HTML5, JavaScript, MySQL, PHP, RequireJS.

## Personal Projects

Self initiated research and development

#### Cartographer

https://github.com/localhost-international/cartographer

#### A decentralised web browser.

Technologies: dat-sdk, ethers.js, IPFS, React Native, Recoil, TypeScript, web3

#### 402

Work in progress

A conceptual "no-backend", peer to peer payment platform.

Technologies: Algorand, "Interledger", web3, Web Payments API

#### Memberships

Self initiated research and development

### Brand Ambassador, Status

May 2020 - present https://ambassador.status.im

Resuming my role as a technical evangelist, promoting and contributing to the next generation of the Web and its ecosystems with Status.

Web and Native Application Research and Development

https://localhost.international/ leslie@localhost.international +44 (0) 79 8328 5634

## Work History (continued)

#### Freelance Developer

November 2012 - June 2013

Clients included: Ballymore, Bill Amberg, Camberwell Arts, Charles Stanley Direct, Citizen Ink, Explosive Brands, Full Signal and Tempero.

Technologies: Facebook Platform, JavaScript, jQuery, MySQL, Node.js, PHP and PhantomJS.

## Senior Developer - Mobile5 (now HYD)

November 2011 - November 2012

Pioneering development of interactive rich media ads that reached millions of mobile users a week and architect of analytics platform: Plus5. Clients included: Audi, Bacardi, Boots, eBay, Honda, John Lewis, Motorola, Nikon, Samsung, Virgin and Vodafone.

Technologies: D3, Facebook APIs, Java, JavaScript, jQuery, MySQL, Objective C, ORMMA, PHP, Phantom.js, SOAP, MRAID, MMSDK, Zepto.js, MRAID, ORMMA, MMSDK, Tera-WURFL.

### Multimedia Development - MulTplx (now MyPlayer)

December 2010 - October 2011

Development of big and small screen digital signage platforms Attract and Allure (now MyPlayer) used in over 50 flagship UK Orange stores. Clients included: Fonehouse, Orange, T-Mobile, Microsoft.

Technologies: Flash, D3, HTML5, JavaScript (jQuery/LocalStorage), JSON, MySQL, OpenX, PHP.

#### Freelance

January 2008 - November 2010

Highlights: Indexhibit CMS, Misha Gravenor and Make Believe, JavaScript.

#### I.T. Officer - British Society for Immunology

September 2006 - January 2008

Highlights: Technical Lead in migration Blackbaud technologies, ASP.NET, JavaScript, PHP, MySQL.

#### I.T. Developer - Interac

March 2005 - March 2006

Highlights: Blosxom, JavaScript, PERL, PHP, ODBC, VB Script.

## Formal Education

Self initiated research and development

Kingston College Art and Design 2002 - 2004

National Diploma in Multimedia BTEC Merit

Southfields Academy

GNVQ in ICT (Distinction), Cisco Networking Academy Program